<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.13">
  <compounddef id="md_vendor_googletest_googlemock_docs__known_issues" kind="page">
    <compoundname>md_vendor_googletest_googlemock_docs_KnownIssues</compoundname>
    <title>KnownIssues</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>As any non-trivial software system, Google <ref refid="class_mock" kindref="compound">Mock</ref> has some known limitations and problems. We are working on improving it, and welcome your help! The follow is a list of issues we know about.</para><para><heading level="2">README contains outdated information on Google <ref refid="class_mock" kindref="compound">Mock</ref>&apos;s compatibility with other testing frameworks</heading>
</para><para>The <computeroutput>README</computeroutput> file in release 1.1.0 still says that Google <ref refid="class_mock" kindref="compound">Mock</ref> only works with Google Test. Actually, you can configure Google <ref refid="class_mock" kindref="compound">Mock</ref> to work with any testing framework you choose.</para><para><heading level="2">Tests failing on machines using Power PC CPUs (e.g. some Macs)</heading>
</para><para><computeroutput>gmock_output_test</computeroutput> and <computeroutput>gmock-printers_test</computeroutput> are known to fail with Power PC CPUs. This is due to portability issues with these tests, and is not an indication of problems in Google <ref refid="class_mock" kindref="compound">Mock</ref> itself. You can safely ignore them.</para><para><heading level="2">Failed to resolve libgtest.so.0 in tests when built against installed Google Test</heading>
</para><para>This only applies if you manually built and installed Google Test, and then built a Google <ref refid="class_mock" kindref="compound">Mock</ref> against it (either explicitly, or because gtest-config was in your path post-install). In this situation, Libtool has a known issue with certain systems&apos; ldconfig setup:</para><para><ulink url="http://article.gmane.org/gmane.comp.sysutils.automake.general/9025">http://article.gmane.org/gmane.comp.sysutils.automake.general/9025</ulink></para><para>This requires a manual run of &quot;sudo ldconfig&quot; after the &quot;sudo make install&quot; for Google Test before any binaries which link against it can be executed. This isn&apos;t a bug in our install, but we should at least have documented it or hacked a work-around into our install. We should have one of these solutions in our next release. </para>    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
